‪SPOOKY IN LOVE
‪I now unveil here for you, the
‪heartwarming love letter of Hwagyeongdang,
‪who was a great poet
‪and painter of her era.
‪[attendees exclaiming]
‪[Hwa-yong laughs]
‪[ghostly shriek]
‪[screaming, clamoring]
‪If this was found in the process
‪of relocating Kang Pyeong-gun's tomb,
‪would that then mean this love letter
‪was in his coffin as well?
‪Yes. How heart-wrenching.
‪It's romantic, don't you think so?
‪Are long-term cold cases
‪really your specialty?
‪Yeah.
‪How would you like another?
‪One that's been cold for over 300 years.
‪Me and you.
‪[upbeat music playing]
‪EPISODE 6
‪[Gang-uk] ‪A couple of ground rules
‪before we start working together.
‪Rule number one: We share everything,
‪and we never go to a scene alone.
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Rule number two:
‪We keep a safe distance
‪when we're on the move.
‪Rule number three:
‪We always leave at least one seat
‪between us when we sit down.
‪So, let me see if I got everything.
‪A male ghost appeared during an event
‪unveiling a 300-year-old love letter
‪that was found
‪while workers relocated an ancient grave.
‪Three hundred? My goodness.
‪You weren't lying.
‪That was a really long time ago.
‪So what can you tell me about the ghost
‪who appeared in front of you?
‪He's an artist, actually.
‪The one who painted
‪Hwagyeongdang's portrait at Yeeon.
‪[Gang-uk] ‪Well, I guess all we need to do
‪is find his remains, right?
‪Not really.
‪He's not the one we should go after.
‪We should look for Hwagyeongdang.
‪Wait, he wrote the letter, right?
‪I don't get it.
‪What's the point of looking
‪for someone else's remains?
‪The thing is…
‪what Dowon told me was a whole different
‪story than the one we heard.
‪[pensive music playing]
‪[birds chirping]
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Apparently,
‪Kang Pyeong-gun, who was of royal blood,
‪started pursuing Hwagyeong,
‪even though she was Dowon's lover.
‪-[Kang Pyeong-gun] What have you found?
‪-He's a painter named Dowon.
‪He and Hwagyeong grew up together.
‪His name means nothing.
‪I care not what it is.
‪All that matters is my Hwagyeong.
‪She's mine.
‪And I must come up with a plan
‪to ensnare him
‪and draw Hwagyeong to my side.
‪I told you to come down a thousand times!
‪You wretched woman,
‪why do you refuse to listen?
‪Do you intend to mock me to the very end?
‪Damn you! You insolent--
‪Who are you? Wait!
‪[onlookers gasp]
‪[noble 1] Good heavens! This man…
‪This man is attacking a nobleman!
‪-[noble 2] How dare he! A nobleman!
‪-[noble 1] He's attacking a nobleman!
‪-Help me, please! He tried to kill me!
‪-Please! Wait! Please don't hurt him!
‪[bureaucrat] ‪Assaulting a nobleman.
‪With the right connections
‪at the police bureau,
‪they can turn it into a crime
‪against the social order,
‪one punishable by death.
‪[sobbing] Let him go.
‪Don't do this to him, I'm begging you!
‪Stop it, please!
‪Stop! Please, stop!
‪[officer] Halt!
‪[Hwagyeong whimpering]
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Kang Pyeong-gun's
‪obsession turned into madness.
‪He held Dowon's life over her head
‪until she had no choice but to marry him.
‪[panting]
‪Where are you bound in such a hurry?
‪How dare you.
‪You tried to deceive me,
‪and you will answer for it.
‪[gasps]
‪No! Wait!
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Hwagyeong attempted to escape
‪Kang Pyeong-gun's tyranny,
‪but she was brutally murdered
‪-before Dowon's eyes.
‪-No!
‪[sobbing]
‪Forgive me, dear.
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Kang Pyeong-gun went so far
‪as to hide Hwagyeong's death.
‪After taking an empty palanquin
‪to Mount Geumgangsan,
‪he spread the ridiculous rumor
‪that Hwagyeongdang had disappeared
‪into the mountains.
‪To this day, no one knows
‪where she was actually buried.
‪[sighs]
‪Hold on a second. Do you think Dowon
‪could have been lying to you?
‪The way I see it,
‪when it comes to romantic relationships,
‪you have to hear both sides of the story.
‪Besides, Hwagyeongdang's love letter
‪was found in Kang Pyeong-gun's tomb, so…
‪He said there's evidence
‪that could prove that wrong.
‪Can you look into that?
‪That's in the "living department."
‪So it's right up your alley.
‪[Gang-uk sighs]
‪[Yeo-ri]
‪By the way, I was doing some research
‪and it turns out Dowon didn't get
‪recognition during his lifetime,
‪but he was later recognized as
‪an important artist thanks to Hwajeopdo.
‪-[Gang-uk sighs] This place is kinda…
‪-[crows cawing]
‪[sighs] I don't know,
‪I think this feels more like
‪Cheon Yeo-ri's department, actually.
‪Oh, wow.
‪What if Dowon was wrong?
‪[clicks tongue]
‪[yelps]
‪Oh! [exhales]
‪Hello, sir.
‪What's with the sickle?
‪[crows squawking]
‪So, what did you say you were looking for?
‪Yes, I'm here
‪because I heard there's a relic
‪of the painter Dowon that was passed
‪down through this family.
‪-Yeah.
‪-Hmm.
‪[sighs]
‪Excuse me, sir.
‪May I take a look at this too?
‪Hmm?
‪[dramatic music playing]
‪So it turns out the two love letters
‪were actually just one.
‪That's right. And she didn't write it
‪for Kang Pyeong-gun either.
‪She wrote it for Dowon.
‪[sighs] I thought this was
‪the Joseon-era version of ‪Ghost‪,
‪but this guy is just a psychopath.
‪A fake empty palanquin? That was the best
‪he could do? So much for royal blood.
‪-[scoffs]
‪-You know what? I think that's why.
‪It's because he was royalty.
‪He couldn't stand
‪the fact that her heart wasn't his.
‪I want to find Hwagyeongdang
‪and reunite her with Dowon
‪once and for all.
‪This whole thing has been keeping her
‪bound to Kang Pyeong-gun for far too long.
‪We have to figure this out.
‪Don't be like that, please.
‪You're not going
‪to walk away now, are you?
‪We're in too deep already.
‪Even if I wanted to back out, I couldn't.
‪The thing is, the prosecution caught wind
‪of what happened last time, you know?
‪And we struggled to keep it under wraps.
‪So I've been thinking,
‪at least until things settle down--
‪-Mrs. Ok--
‪-Anyway, that Ju Sin-ho painting
‪-you gave me last time really helped…
‪-[phone buzzing]
‪Excuse me. It's Cheon Yeo-ri.
‪What does she want?
‪Hello, Ms. Cheon. [laughs]
‪We're talking a lot lately,
‪aren't we, huh?
‪Ah! Of course.
‪Okay, sure. See you tomorrow.
‪You don't think Cheon Yeo-ri
‪could've caught on to something, do you?
‪No, no way.
‪Well, I'll find out
‪when I meet with her, I guess.
‪[sighs]
‪Yes, so in other news, I'm meeting
‪with Yeeon's director tomorrow.
‪I'm going to see
‪if anything else comes up.
‪Hmm. Okay, no worries.
‪I'll join you after work.
‪Hmm? I can go there by myself, you know.
‪Uh, you can't do that.
‪Remember rule number one?
‪We have to share everything we learn,
‪and we can't go to a scene alone,
‪that's what we agreed on.
‪And besides, we have
‪a team dinner afterward.
‪Team dinner?
‪Yeah. We've earned it
‪after all this hard work.
‪[laughs] That pork rind place again?
‪Ah. That sounds pretty good.
‪To be safe, I'll bring an extra shirt.
‪[laughs]
‪Well, by the way, um,
‪I wanted to do a little more digging
‪before asking, um… Mmm…
‪Where did the artwork on display
‪in the Reina Hotel come from?
‪Oh, the artwork.
‪Um, our art team handles all of that.
‪We usually get them through
‪Gallery Cheon, which my aunt runs.
‪Why?
‪Is there a problem, or…
‪Oh, no, no. Don't worry about it.
‪It's not that there's anything wrong
‪with Reina or Gallery Cheon.
‪It's just that Reina's name came up
‪during an art distribution investigation.
‪ACQUISITIONS
‪AND TRANSACTION RECORD
‪OF ARTWORK PLACED IN HOTELS
‪Are these all the art pieces
‪Reina has on display right now?
‪Yes.
‪I sent each of the transfer files
‪separately to your email.
‪Great, so what I need now
‪is a list with all the artwork
‪Reina has purchased
‪through Gallery Cheon
‪over the past ten years.
‪Check all the market values
‪against what we paid.
‪Bring that over to me
‪once you're done, Mr. Bong.
‪And don't tell anyone. No one can know.
‪Got it.
‪I'm busy, what do you want?
‪Have a seat.
‪What is it?
‪So… about the Reina Hotel case
‪you mentioned, how's that going?
‪-Again with this artwork stuff?
‪-I'm just curious, don't be like that.
‪Whatever. What exactly do you wanna know?
‪You said someone started digging
‪and got shut down. Who was it?
‪[sighs] Whatever, no point in hiding
‪anything from you anyway.
‪So originally, Nam Ji-hun
‪from Unit Three was looking into it.
‪Then the higher-ups
‪told him to shut it down.
‪Now I'm doing it.
‪If the money's gone,
‪that's probably laundering.
‪But since the artwork disappeared,
‪bribery's more like it, isn't it?
‪Well, yeah, that's
‪what I've been thinking too.
‪But why would the Chief Prosecutor
‪do the dirty work himself? I don't get it.
‪Exactly.
‪I also thought that was weird.
‪That's why I'm looking into it.
‪There's a lot I don't know,
‪but at least I know
‪where the money went now.
‪Reina, right?
‪You're acting weird.
‪You're obsessed with Reina.
‪You're up to something, aren't you?
‪I'm not up to anything. What do you mean?
‪I'm completely swamped
‪just dealing with my cold cases.
‪[inhales sharply]
‪Well, okay. So it's not Reina? Is that it?
‪It's not Reina.
‪[exhales]
‪I'm going there later. Wanna come with me?
‪I can't. I have somewhere to be.
‪Great work, by the way.
‪[Seo-hyeon] Hey. [scoffs]
‪Well, that's surprising.
‪You're more of a romantic
‪than I thought, Ms. Cheon.
‪Of course it's interesting to me,
‪I mean, they're my ancestors.
‪But why are you so emotionally invested
‪in a love letter from that long ago?
‪-[both chuckle]
‪-You're right, I know.
‪It's not the romance.
‪There's more to it than that.
‪It felt like the words of someone who
‪was anticipating something, you know?
‪A final farewell.
‪I don't know why,
‪but it really stuck with me.
‪I wonder where Hwagyeongdang
‪was buried. I'm really curious.
‪I just don't get it.
‪Why would someone with as much
‪on your plate as you, Ms. Cheon,
‪be so curious about something like that?
‪[both chuckle]
‪Well, if there's anything you'd like
‪to know that isn't in the public records,
‪you might want to check out the alma mater
‪of my late father, the founding chairman.
‪All the records related
‪to Kang Pyeong-gun were donated
‪to the Yeeon Museum,
‪so they're all in one place.
‪We're planning to donate the letter too,
‪once it's officially unveiled.
‪-[both chuckle]
‪-[knock on door]
‪-Yes?
‪-[door opens]
‪-Oh, Mr. Kang.
‪-Hi, sorry I'm late.
‪-Just made it back from the airport.
‪-Oh, not at all.
‪You made it just in time. Have a seat.
‪We were just catching up over the phone.
‪That's right. She told me you were coming,
‪so I insisted on joining.
‪[Hwa-yong]
‪The trip here must've been so tiring.
‪-[Min-hwan] Not at all.
‪-[Hwa-yong] Oh, my goodness.
‪[exhales]
‪[Seo-hyeon] Gang-uk?
‪-Um, what?
‪-"Um, what"?
‪Hey, what are you doing here?
‪What are you doing here?
‪[Yeo-ri]
‪You and Ms. Lee seem pretty close.
‪[Min-hwan] Oh, she's close with my mother.
‪Anyway, talk about good timing.
‪I almost missed you there.
‪Where are you coming in from?
‪They found some artifacts
‪at the Baekhyeon Leisure Town site
‪so they had to stop construction.
‪-Hmm.
‪-I went there to sort things out.
‪-Oh.
‪For you.
‪W-What's this?
‪I was on a business trip in Europe
‪and I thought they'd suit you.
‪Thank you. No one's
‪given me gloves before.
‪They're lovely.
‪Mm-hmm.
‪You're not here
‪because of what I said, are you?
‪What do you mean?
‪Ah, this is where
‪the money went, isn't it?
‪I get it now.
‪That's why you're here so often.
‪I know something's up.
‪What is it? Just say it.
‪-Spit it out, come on. What?
‪-Ah, it's nothing. Nothing's going on.
‪-Hey, wait for me!
‪-Hey, don't do that.
‪[Seo-hyeon] Oh, come on.
‪-Just for a minute.
‪-Get off me.
‪-So we meet again.
‪-So we do.
‪Oh. I know you.
‪You're the famous Cheon Yeo-ri, right?
‪Nice to meet you. Uh…
‪I'm Prosecutor Im Seo-hyeon. Prosecutor Ma
‪and I work at the same district office.
‪I saw the article about you two,
‪by the way.
‪Uh, congratulations.
‪So when's the, um, engagement ceremony?
‪Oh. That would've been amazing.
‪But they just published
‪a follow-up article.
‪-Sadly, they were just rumors.
‪-[Seo-hyeon] Oh, really?
‪[sighs]
‪Huh. Uh…
‪We're going to grab some dinner.
‪Why don't you join us?
‪When did I say yes to that?
‪[Seo-hyeon] Oh, come on. You always
‪have dinner by yourself anyway.
‪[groans]
‪Let's call it a team dinner
‪so it's an excuse to eat together.
‪Right? Let's go together.
‪Come on, just forget it.
‪Uh, let's just… let' s get out of here.
‪That sounds good.
‪Let's go. Together.
‪The four of us.
‪[Seo-hyeon laughs] Look at this.
‪Check this out. We took this
‪the last time we came here.
‪Whoa. You two have
‪the couple selfie thing down.
‪That's… That's not a couple selfie.
‪Im insisted we take a picture since we
‪were here, so I just went along with it--
‪Well, you look good together.
‪[footsteps approaching]
‪[clears throat]
‪Thank you.
‪All right, let's have a toast then.
‪Our beers are here.
‪-Sure.
‪-Cheers!
‪Oh, come on…
‪[gulps, sighs]
‪Ah. I feel like you had to tone down
‪the meal because of us, so I…
‪I feel bad.
‪You know, since we work
‪for the government,
‪we have no choice
‪but to follow public service rules
‪so we have to pay separately.
‪The pasta here is really good.
‪And the ramen too, it's good.
‪-You eat ramen often?
‪-Mm-hmm.
‪Sometimes I do.
‪It's a good quick meal, very convenient.
‪[Seo-hyeon] Oh, really? I always thought
‪people from ‪chaebol‪ families
‪only ate specially prepared meals,
‪fancy fine dining, 12-course feasts
‪and all that kinda stuff.
‪[chuckles]
‪So, if you like ramen,
‪we should have it by the Hangang River.
‪It tastes even better
‪when you're by the riverbank.
‪I can't wait to go there
‪and have some ramen with you two.
‪Can you just… just, you know… just…
‪[Seo-hyeon] What'd I say?
‪What about you, Prosecutor Ma?
‪Have you ever had ramen
‪by the Hangang River?
‪-Yeah, well--
‪-Oh, he lives for it.
‪Back when
‪we worked at the Southern District,
‪we ran into each other while jogging
‪the day after a team dinner,
‪got ramen for our hangovers,
‪and went to the office together.
‪I didn't know people
‪ate ramen for hangovers.
‪I'll have to try that out,
‪you know, at some point.
‪That's nice.
‪Just let me know when, I wanna try it too.
‪What?
‪Of course. Let's do it. It's a plan.
‪Ramen by the river,
‪the four us. [chuckles]
‪There. Have some.
‪-My goodness.
‪-Eat it, come on.
‪Go ahead.
‪[choking]
‪Oh…
‪[coughing]
‪-You did that for me, Gang-uk?
‪-No, just… eat.
‪Are you okay with beer?
‪You don't like it that much.
‪[Yeo-ri chuckles] I drink beer sometimes.
‪You really surprised me there.
‪You're a lot more thoughtful
‪than I thought you'd be, Prosecutor Ma.
‪Judging by the way
‪you treat Prosecutor Im,
‪it's safe to say you're pretty caring.
‪[scoffs]
‪Well, if I'm being honest,
‪he surprised me too.
‪I didn't know Gang-uk had a sweet side.
‪[Gang-uk] I wasn't being thoughtful.
‪I was just worried
‪she'd spill the food all over herself.
‪-She's really clumsy, actually--
‪-Exactly, and that was thoughtful.
‪-[sighs]
‪-You love me.
‪What? No, I don't. Waiter?
‪Can we get another round here, please?
‪Oh. You're the designated driver, right?
‪-[driver] Yes, hi.
‪-There you go, thanks.
‪-Sure.
‪-Where'd you park? I can give you a ride.
‪It's fine.
‪I'll go get my car in the morning.
‪-I'll take a cab.
‪-[phone buzzing]
‪-[Seo-hyeon] You sure?
‪-Mm-hmm. Later.
‪-All right, see you tomorrow.
‪-[Gang-uk] Bye.
‪Well, next time, we'll meet up
‪by the river for ramen.
‪-[engine starts]
‪-Thanks again, sir.
‪-I'll give you a ride.
‪-Oh. It's all right.
‪Uh, I think I'll just…
‪I'll just walk home.
‪To get some fresh air.
‪Can I walk you there?
‪[chuckles softly] That's okay.
‪-Get home safe.
‪-Mm-hmm.
‪[engine starts]
‪Oh, no. That's not the right department.
‪Don't send that to them. Yeah.
‪Oh, I'll… I'll call you back tomorrow,
‪okay? Bye.
‪Yeo-ri, what did Ms. Lee say?
‪Any developments or anything?
‪-No developments.
‪-Oh.
‪By the way, that was a close call, right?
‪I did good, didn't I?
‪Yeah, that was really nice of you.
‪Im sure loved it.
‪I didn't do it for Im, you know.
‪I was just looking out for you, Yeo-ri.
‪Don't you get it?
‪That doesn't make any sense, does it?
‪Im Seo-hyeon is the one
‪who would be affected if we touched.
‪And Min-hwan was right,
‪you were thoughtful and sweet.
‪Sweet? Don't say that, Yeo-ri.
‪You know that's not fair, come on.
‪If I'm being honest here,
‪I was so busy watching Min-hwan
‪being sly, and trying to manage Seo-hyeon,
‪I couldn't even tell if the pasta
‪was going through my mouth or my nose.
‪Wait, Yeo-ri.
‪-Are you a little bit--
‪-Of course I'm not.
‪Ah, I didn't finish.
‪How do you know what I was gonna say?
‪Whatever you say, my answer won't change.
‪[upbeat, romantic music playing]
‪Did my hands touch you?
‪Um, I'm not sure. But I don't think so.
‪Uh, since your accident,
‪have you ever done something like this?
‪This is my first time.
‪Uh, and I think, as far as I know,
‪only my hands trigger the effect.
‪Good. I think we're fine, then.
‪And if not, I'm totally okay with it.
‪Uh, please just… don't worry about it.
‪So, for now…
‪uh, let's just keep an eye on you.
‪If you don't see anything by tomorrow,
‪then I guess you should be in the clear.
‪You really don't have to worry, Yeo-ri.
‪It's fine. We'll just handle things
‪as they come.
‪Still, if you see something,
‪give me a call.
‪Okay.
‪He won't see them. He won't see them.
‪Of course he won't see them.
‪He's not calling,
‪but he shouldn't be calling anyway.
‪-He's not gonna see them.
‪-[phone buzzing]
‪He's not-- [gasps]
‪Do you see a ghost?
‪No. I don't see them.
‪I'm calling to let you know.
‪[sighs]
‪Oh my gosh, you scared me.
‪I thought you saw a ghost.
‪I said call me
‪if you see anything, didn't I?
‪[stammering] I'm sorry.
‪[sighs]
‪-You shouldn't meet him.
‪-[shouting]
‪-Come out. Show yourself! Who's there?
‪-…choice. I have to do it for the clan.
‪[character] ‪Come on, there's
‪gotta be something else we can do.
‪-[panting]
‪-‪Wait. I just thought of something!
‪-[phone buzzes]
‪-[gasps]
‪Yep, hello?
‪How about now?
‪I'm a little worried.
‪Oh. Pretty sure I don't see anything.
‪At least not yet.
‪I'm gonna call you if I do.
‪-Gang-uk…
‪-Yes?
‪This isn't gonna work.
‪I'll just handle this case
‪on my own, like I always do.
‪[stammering] Wait a minute, wait a minute.
‪Uh, I don't see them,
‪but even if I do, it's not like
‪it's my first time experiencing this.
‪I'm used to it by now.
‪I have my own ways
‪of dealing with them now.
‪I'm not on your level,
‪but I'm not that bad.
‪Even so…
‪And the truth is, I'm curious too.
‪This centuries-old mystery
‪has really drawn me in.
‪I have to see how it ends.
‪Okay, sounds good.
‪But you have to call me
‪the second anything happens, got it?
‪Okay.
‪Sleep well.
‪[phone beeps]
‪[upbeat, romantic music playing]
‪[Gang-uk] ‪No sign of them.
‪No need to worry.
‪PROSECUTOR MA
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Great, I'm glad.
‪[Baek] Come in.
‪You wanted to see me?
‪Here, let's have a cup of tea.
‪You're more of a coffee person,
‪though, aren't you?
‪Hmm. Well, um, I'm staying away
‪from caffeine for now.
‪Come to think of it,
‪you look a little pale right now.
‪What happened? You're not sick, are you?
‪They said it's nothing specific.
‪[chuckles] At my age,
‪that's the best you can get.
‪I'm sorry to hear that.
‪I haven't been calling you.
‪I'll do that more often now.
‪Great.
‪Yeo-ri, I'd rather you came by more often.
‪[chuckles]
‪Instead of waiting
‪for me to call you over.
‪Yeah, that was 12 years ago.
‪He had a heart transplant.
‪But I don't see
‪anything else other than that.
‪Of course. I'm telling you because I know
‪the donor's identity is confidential.
‪How long will it take?
‪Yeah. ASAP.
‪PRELIMINARY BACKGROUND CHECK REPORT
‪SUBJECT: MA GANG-UK
‪[doctor] 200 joules.
‪[nurse] 200 joules.
‪-[doctor] Clear.
‪-[thumps]
‪[alarm beeping]
‪-[defibrillator surges]
‪-[doctor] Clear.
‪[nurse]
‪The donor's heart has been removed, sir.
‪[heart beating]
‪[groaning]
‪[Hwa-yong lecturing faintly on phone]
‪-Pil-dong?
‪-Hmm?
‪Option one or option two?
‪-Hmm, just two?
‪-Yeah.
‪-Option one.
‪-Okay, donkkaseu.
‪-[both laugh]
‪-Of course.
‪[Hwa-yong] ‪…violence is committed
‪in the name of love…
‪-Donkkaseu, cool.
‪-…we made the decision to make this letter
‪-available to the public…
‪-Hey. Wanna grab lunch?
‪-You go ahead.
‪-[Hyeong-min] Are you sure?
‪-We're getting donkkaseu.
‪-[Gang-uk] Enjoy.
‪[Hwa-yong] ‪After we finally release it,
‪I intend to donate it in accordance…
‪LEE HWA-YONG,
‪DIRECTOR OF YEEON FOUNDATION
‪…with the last and final wishes
‪of my late father,
‪first director of the Yeeon Foundation,
‪to my alma mater.‪ [chuckles]
‪That's right.
‪I heard the founding chairman
‪donated just about all the old records
‪on Kang Pyeong-gun to his old university.
‪Well, every investigation's
‪gotta start somewhere, right?
‪And these Kang Pyeong-gun records might
‪just lead us exactly where we need to go.
‪So, I'm thinking I'll swing by after work.
‪Oh. I was actually planning to go there.
‪Oh! Well, let's go together.
‪Okay, sure.
‪-Mr. Bong.
‪-Yes?
‪Come a little closer.
‪About this afternoon's executive meeting,
‪anything special on the agenda?
‪Uh, no, not particularly, ma'am.
‪Okay, well, in that case, you're going
‪to be running the meeting yourself.
‪Yes.
‪Oh. Hey, Ms. Eom.
‪Do you think Ms. Cheon's
‪been acting a little strange lately?
‪Yes I do, Mr. Bong. You noticed too?
‪Ah. I knew you'd be
‪the right person to ask.
‪I guess so. She's been a little
‪less guarded than she used to be, right?
‪You know what?
‪I feel like she's more trusting now.
‪She's letting people in.
‪Especially this guy.
‪Ah! You saw what happened in there.
‪She went and singled me out.
‪She said, "Mr. Bong,
‪come a little closer."
‪And then she left
‪the executive meeting in my hands.
‪[laughing] It's clear as day by now.
‪What is clear?
‪Well, that she sees me as her right-hand.
‪[laughing]
‪Too much pressure for one person.
‪Do you want to know
‪what's "too much," Mr. Bong? You are.
‪Ah. You're just jealous.
‪I'm an easygoing guy. [chuckling]
‪[door opens]
‪[Gang-uk] Yeah. Yes, I'm here.
‪Sure, sounds great. Thanks!
‪He put in a word for us.
‪Oh, right.
‪Rule number two, right?
‪Keep a safe distance. Sorry.
‪[sighs] The weather's amazing, isn't it?
‪I think my balance is off.
‪I keep pulling to the left.
‪[both chuckle]
‪-Welcome.
‪-Hello.
‪I just talked to my boss on the phone.
‪-He told me to help you out however I can.
‪-We appreciate it.
‪-This way, Ms. Cheon.
‪-Mm-hmm.
‪[Gang-uk]
‪So many old documents in here, huh?
‪[chuckles]
‪This is the Yeeon Foundation section.
‪All donated documents are here.
‪Is that Kang Pyeong-gun's?
‪This is a record of property inheritance
‪the king issued to Lord Kang Pyeong-gun.
‪Kang Pyeong-gun's name is right here.
‪It specifies every room,
‪even the number of kitchen bays.
‪It's more detailed than I thought.
‪Ah, is there something like
‪a blueprint of the house or a floor plan?
‪There is something along
‪those lines. It's called a ‪Jetaekdo.
‪This was Kang Pyeong-gun's residence.
‪Wow. Is it okay
‪if I take a picture of this?
‪Wow.
‪This is Kang Pyeong-gun's
‪personal anthology.
‪You could think of it
‪as a collection of essays.
‪HWAPYEONG ANTHOLOGY
‪So we have these
‪and the records about his home.
‪Do you have anything else here?
‪There's one more,
‪his personal travel journal.
‪Give me a moment.
‪Oh! Yeo-ri, wait a minute.
‪Hmm?
‪Oh, watch out!
‪-What are you doing? Be careful.
‪-Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
‪Huh?
‪What's that?
‪Take… Take a picture.
‪[camera shutter clicking]
‪"The camellia tree
‪by my late wife's grave."
‪That has to be a reference to
‪where Hwagyeongdang was buried,
‪-don't you think?
‪-Yeah, I think so too.
‪"I will look upon it for the rest of
‪my days to find comfort for my heartache."
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪Wait a second, so that means
‪Hwagyeongdang's camellia tree
‪was visible from his residence, right?
‪[Gang-uk] ‪And since Yeeon now stands
‪on the old site
‪of Kang Pyeong-gun's residence…
‪Well, there you go.
‪There's no such thing as a perfect crime.
‪Even after so long,
‪the truth always ends up coming out.
‪Such a horrible obsession.
‪Anyway, we've got a problem.
‪There's no way
‪we can check under the tree.
‪We can't just dig it up.
‪It belongs to the museum.
‪Yeah, I know. Ugh.
‪And we can't just be honest about it,
‪because they'd think
‪we're completely nuts.
‪Plus, this would be
‪a disgrace to their ancestors,
‪so that is not an option.
‪We'll have to find a way
‪to make it happen somehow.
‪Hwagyeongdang…
‪really needs to be set free.
‪Yeah.
‪[sighs]
‪Is that Cheon Yeo-ri, or am I wrong?
‪And who is that man?
‪Director Ok, hi.
‪Is Cheon Yeo-ri interested
‪in the gallery, by any chance?
‪She's been coming here a lot lately.
‪Cheon Yeo-ri?
‪Has she been asking questions
‪about the hotel's artwork
‪or anything like that?
‪No, nothing like that.
‪She's just here with some guy right now.
‪Oh, I see. [chuckles]
‪And the guy she's with,
‪does it happen to be Kang Min-hwan?
‪[Hwa-yong] ‪No way.
‪I'd recognize Min-hwan in a heartbeat.
‪And also,
‪he'd definitely stop by to say hello.
‪[Gye-hui chuckles] Right.
‪Anyway, I'll try to drop by
‪sometime soon to see you.
‪There's something I need to tell you.
‪Great, I hope it's good news, right?
‪Ah, yes. [chuckles]
‪-Mom.
‪-Hmm?
‪What did Ms. Lee say?
‪Were Yeo-ri and Min-hwan there together?
‪I don't think it was him, actually. No.
‪Are Cheon Yeo-ri and Min-hwan
‪actually seeing each other?
‪You saw the other article, right?
‪They're not dating yet.
‪Don't say "yet." Come on.
‪That makes it sound like they will date.
‪Mom, if Min-hwan and Yeo-ri get married,
‪that leaves us
‪in a terrible position, doesn't it?
‪[groans]
‪We'll just have to play that card again
‪if it doesn't pan out.
‪You mean that thing about the ghosts?
‪We can't play that card, all right?
‪We can't prove that.
‪People are already spreading rumors.
‪I heard they came from Cha Gi-u's side
‪after the engagement ended.
‪-Hey, wait…
‪-Huh?
‪Is Cha Gi-u back in Korea?
‪Huh? Oh, yeah.
‪Came back last month, I heard.
‪Okay.
‪[Gong-jun] Oh! Look! I won!
‪Where are you going?
‪[scoffs] She's making a run for it.
‪So you want the real reason?
‪There isn't a "real" reason
‪and a "fake" reason, is there?
‪I wanna know what really happened,
‪not the PR version.
‪People said you went abroad to study
‪as soon as it was called off.
‪I heard the rumors you've been spreading.
‪And the thing is,
‪they line up with my theory, so…
‪And what's your theory, Ms. Cheon?
‪I think, maybe there was
‪something about my cousin
‪that was too much for you to handle, huh?
‪Something I couldn't handle?
‪-Like what, Ms. Cheon?
‪-Well, you know…
‪Something involving ghosts
‪and the supernatural.
‪I'd like you to testify to that.
‪When the time comes, all right?
‪What happens then?
‪[Ko] No, they were just working
‪on the place when they found it.
‪-Yeah.
‪-[exhales]
‪No. No, no. You can't.
‪You'll end up in huge trouble
‪if you cover up an artifact like that.
‪Mm-hmm. Well, first things first,
‪you need to report it.
‪I'll head over there.
‪I'll check it out. Maybe over the weekend.
‪Uh-huh. I'm at work right now.
‪Uh-huh. Hmm.
‪Oh, boy.
‪My parents are fixing up a wall
‪at their place,
‪and it turns out part of it was connected
‪to an old fortress site or something.
‪-[Hyeong-min] They found an artifact?
‪-[Ko] Hmm.
‪[Hyeong-min] I heard the government
‪pays you for that kinda stuff, right?
‪Do you know how much?
‪[Ko] Yeah, well, I'm sure
‪it's peanuts anyway. Hey--
‪-You're always like that.
‪-Huh?
‪All… All you think about is money.
‪Well, everyone needs money
‪to survive, you know?
‪Sure. You know what else I need? Food.
‪-Team dinner tonight? What do you think?
‪-Oh!
‪Let's have pork rind. How does that sound?
‪-Next time, next time.
‪-Wait a second, hold on. Listen to me.
‪You are going to love this place.
‪They actually age it right there.
‪-Aged pork rind. They do it right there.
‪-Cool. Next time, next time.
‪You… I swear to God,
‪I'm sick of looking at his face.
‪I mean, you're really
‪something else, you know that?
‪Did I do something to you?
‪Always with your sharp exits.
‪You're like cutting out of here
‪like a chef with a knife.
‪You should do that too, actually.
‪You too.
‪See what I mean? Come on…
‪[sighs]
‪I bet this is all because of a lady.
‪Right? You know who, huh?
‪Oh, right! Yeah. Uh-huh. Okay.
‪Yeah. That girl, right?
‪That woman is probably out there.
‪[Hyeong-min] ‪Mm-hmm.
‪[Ko] ‪The only person who can turn Gang-uk
‪into the king of leaving work on the dot:
‪his grandmother, Mrs. Pang Myo-sun.
‪[slow, romantic music playing]
‪Yeo-ri. You're here early.
‪[sighs] Gang-uk.
‪Oh, I'm a little early.
‪But you're a little early too.
‪Ah. I wanted to be the first one here.
‪I was a minute too late.
‪[both chuckle]
‪It's nice being here, huh?
‪Makes me feel like I'm back in school.
‪Yeah. And it's quiet,
‪so we won't run into anyone we know.
‪Ah! Listen, I came up with an idea
‪-so we can search under the tree.
‪-Did you?
‪If you find an artifact
‪while building on private property,
‪you're required to stop construction.
‪Cultural Heritage Law. Yup!
‪-Oh, that's right. You would know.
‪-[chuckles]
‪In any case,
‪if that's our move,
‪I need to pull out my ace in the hole.
‪Hmm?
‪[Hwa-yong] Hold on.
‪You want to buy our camellia tree?
‪You mentioned it last time.
‪Even in the south,
‪camellias with that bright
‪magenta color are hard to find.
‪I want it for myself.
‪You know what? Honestly,
‪I thought you were coming here so often
‪because you were interested
‪in the business.
‪-[both chuckle]
‪-But this is unexpected.
‪Actually, some of the other things
‪you've shown interest in
‪have been a little unusual too.
‪-You think so?
‪-Oh. Let me think here…
‪Well, this camellia
‪meant a lot to my late father.
‪He spent years taking care of it.
‪And our visitors seem to love it too.
‪People are always in front of it,
‪taking pictures and all that.
‪I don't really see why--
‪I wanna keep it at home, you know?
‪Put it in my yard, so I can always see it.
‪Oh, but you can come here
‪whenever you want.
‪Hmm…
‪Wait a minute,
‪if you don't want to sell it to me,
‪how about a trade instead?
‪Uh, for what?
‪Well, our family has
‪a really rare pine tree, it's very old.
‪Is that so? Huh.
‪You and Director Ok have been
‪really close lately, haven't you?
‪Well, you know,
‪we're in the same line of work after all.
‪She'll know what pine tree it is.
‪Talk to her about it,
‪if you want. She'll tell you.
‪Maybe she's already told you.
‪[phone buzzing]
‪Ms. Lee, hi.
‪So you talked to Director Ok on the phone?
‪Great.
‪Then I'll prepare for the work on my end.
‪Bye.
‪[chuckles]
‪[phone buzzing]
‪Hmm?
‪Yes, hello?
‪I'll be right there, thank you.
‪Hi, Yeo-ri.
‪I checked with the Korea Heritage Service,
‪and it looks like
‪we can proceed as planned.
‪That's great.
‪-Yeo-ri?
‪-Yes?
‪Is everything okay? You seem…
‪Sorry about that.
‪I'm gonna have to call you back.
‪Good evening.
‪Go ahead.
‪[somber music playing]
‪You're here.
‪Grandma, hi.
‪What's going on? How are you?
‪Nothing, I just had
‪a little spell, honey, that's all.
‪I was lucky Min-hwan was there.
‪He called an ambulance
‪before anything worse happened.
‪No one else knows about this.
‪Especially not Director Ok.
‪Oh, Grandma…
‪I'm not dead yet, you know?
‪Goodness, this isn't like you.
‪Hmm.
‪I'm so sorry.
‪[music continues]
‪I'll go check on Ms. Cheon.
‪[sighs]
‪I wonder if everything's all right.
‪Maybe I should go to her place?
‪No, too much.
‪I didn't want to mention this,
‪for your sake.
‪But I don't really know
‪how much time I have left.
‪What do you mean?
‪What are you talking about?
‪You know what I was
‪most worried about after I collapsed?
‪Cheon Yeo-ri.
‪"I can't leave her all by herself."
‪Cha Gi-u, your ex-fiancé.
‪He's been spreading rumors about
‪why you called off the wedding.
‪Bury this story with a bigger one.
‪This is our chance
‪to prove them all wrong.
‪Yeo-ri, let's put the gossip to rest.
‪You must announce
‪the engagement to Min-hwan.
‪I'll admit it, this battle
‪for ownership will be tough.
‪I know they've got
‪plenty of support right now.
‪But doing that would
‪only treat the symptoms.
‪That approach isn't going to fix
‪what's really wrong.
‪I'll show them what I'm capable of,
‪and I'll win the shareholders' trust,
‪I promise you.
‪[chuckles]
‪The issue here is time.
‪I have to start
‪the succession process right away.
‪You remember Director Gong
‪and Director Jang, don't you?
‪They were really close
‪with the late chairman.
‪They have enough shares between them
‪to hold the deciding vote.
‪As far as I remember,
‪they've always been neutral.
‪Yes. And that's exactly why
‪we're going to approach
‪Director Jang first.
‪Chairwoman Baek
‪wants to formalize the succession
‪at the next shareholders' meeting.
‪Your mother loved Reina so much, you know?
‪And Siena, but that goes without saying.
‪If you want to protect them,
‪then I'm begging you,
‪listen to me this time around.
‪Remember last time?
‪The stock jumped
‪as soon as the article dropped.
‪Min-hwan will have your back.
‪He'll be valuable to you in many ways.
‪You've known him since you were kids.
‪[chuckles]
‪[sighs]
‪[phone buzzes]
‪Gosh, Yeo-ri, why has it been so…
‪It's been so hard to reach you.
‪You said you'd call me later.
‪Is, uh… Is everything okay?
‪My grandmother wasn't feeling well,
‪so I went to visit her at the hospital.
‪Oh. I'm sorry. Is she okay?
‪She's all right. She's doing better now.
‪That's a relief.
‪Are you okay, Yeo-ri?
‪Yeah. By the way, I talked to Ms. Lee.
‪She accepted. We closed the deal.
‪We'll get it done
‪while the museum's closed.
‪Okay.
‪So I guess we should be good to go.
‪-Yeah.
‪-Yeo-ri.
‪Shall we have a team dinner?
‪What do you say?
‪I was thinking we could have ramen
‪by the Hangang River.
‪We'll see, Gang-uk.
‪Well, see you at the museum.
‪-Okay.
‪-Bye.
‪YEEON MUSEUM OF ART
‪TEMPORARY CLOSURE
‪[thunder rumbling]
‪Looks like we're in for some heavy rain.
‪Ugh. Maybe we should do it
‪some other time.
‪What if Ms. Lee changes her mind
‪out of the blue?
‪-Let's go ahead with it.
‪-Okay.
‪Let's get started.
‪Okay, come on, let's begin!
‪-Yes, sir!
‪Let's start over here.
‪I told them to dig deep.
‪Once the coffin's exposed, we'll stop
‪the work immediately and call it in.
‪Oh, the papers. Do we have all we need?
‪I filled out the report ahead of time.
‪Everything's ready to go.
‪Okay.
‪Once we call it in,
‪they'll send someone to check it out.
‪Before we know it,
‪they'll be out here inspecting the coffin.
‪-[phone buzzing]
‪-[Hwa-yong] Director Ok, hello.
‪They've just started digging.
‪Yeah, I…
‪Is it just me, or does something feel off?
‪To be honest,
‪it's a beautiful tree,
‪but it's just a common camellia.
‪Why would she trade
‪for such a valuable ancient tree?
‪Doesn't that seem a little strange to you?
‪[laughs]
‪Maybe she's just obsessed
‪with that magenta color.
‪[laughs] That's her.
‪Yeo-ri's always been like that.
‪Once her heart is set on something,
‪she won't stop until it's hers. [chuckles]
‪Anyway, congrats on your purchase.
‪That's a really valuable tree,
‪so good for you.
‪-Why, thank you.
‪-Bye.
‪-[blowing]
‪-[phone buzzing]
‪INCOMING CALL - SECRETARY WANG,
‪CHAIRWOMAN'S OFFICE
‪[groans]
‪What happens if we don't find anything?
‪Oh! It's raining.
‪Come on, Yeo-ri. Come on.
‪-Get under the canopy!
‪-[foreman] Stop what you're doing…
‪-[worker] Oh, it's pouring!
‪-…and get under the canopy.
‪Come inside, come inside!
‪Damn it, we barely started.
‪Hey, what's with the family dinner?
‪Are we in trouble or something?
‪Ha-ri, was it you? What did you do?
‪I didn't do anything.
‪Well, never mind then.
‪Why'd you get so worked up?
‪It's no big deal,
‪just a family dinner, settle down.
‪I don't buy that. I think it's weird.
‪Min-hwan was invited too. Oh, no.
‪They're not about
‪to get engaged, are they?
‪It would really suck for us if they did.
‪Getting engaged is no simple task.
‪Remember Cha Gi-u? That fell apart.
‪They called it off
‪on the day of the wedding.
‪That's true. Cheon Yeo-ri has a way
‪of messing things up for herself, right?
‪They're not getting engaged tonight.
‪How do you know that?
‪Mommy, call Director Gong for a minute.
‪It's not getting better.
‪We're gonna have to call it a day.
‪Yes, safety first, you're right.
‪-Let's just call it for now.
‪-[phone buzzing]
‪The weather's been crazy
‪these days, right?
‪I know, man.
‪It's getting crazier every year.
‪Grandma, hi.
‪A family dinner?
‪Min-hwan's going too?
‪Okay, I'll be there.
‪Yeo-ri, what's going on?
‪I…
‪think I'm going to have to get engaged.
‪Huh?
‪Uh, what do you mean?
‪[thunderclap]
‪[dramatic music playing]
‪Good evening.
‪-Oh, there you are.
‪-Hello. Hi.
‪To think I'd see you here.
‪Happy to be here.
‪Great, shall we get started then?
‪Actually, I have something to say
‪before we start.
‪Hold on a minute.
‪Someone else will be joining us soon.
‪We should wait till he's here.
‪Just tell me this.
‪Did you hold hands with my cousin?
‪I'd like you to testify to that.
‪When the time comes, all right?
‪Who is it?
‪We have one more guest.
‪[upbeat music playing]
‪Hello, everyone.
‪I'm Ma Gang-uk. It's a pleasure.
‪Prosecutor Ma Gang-uk and I…
‪are getting engaged.
‪[music continues]
‪SPOOKY IN LOVE
‪[Baek] ‪So it's not about business
‪with Prosecutor Ma?
‪You have feelings
‪for each other, is that true?
‪I like Yeo-ri a lot.
‪We're getting engaged and I'm excited.
‪Tell me something, dear.
‪What's your zodiac sign?
‪-What?
‪-Your sign.
‪[Yeo-ri] ‪My sign?
‪[Ko] ‪Okay then, next.
‪-[Gang-uk] Back then…
‪-I was playing hard to get.
‪You're gonna call off the engagement,
‪that's what you'll do.
‪-You're kidding me.
‪-How about we work together?
‪We both want to break them up,
‪and I know how to do it.
‪[Gye-hui] ‪You remember
‪what happened six years ago, right?
‪I want to know the real reason
‪you broke off your engagement in exchange.
‪[Baek] ‪I think you should have a meeting.
‪I think Director Ok has started openly
‪trying to keep you in check.
‪CIVIL SERVANT PERSONNEL RECORD
‪MA GANG-UK
‪[Min-hwan] ‪Yeo-ri can never get engaged.
‪Not to Ma Gang-uk, or anyone else.
‪[Ha-ri] ‪I've got you now, Cheon Yeo-ri.